[roaring]
[narrator] Strange beasts
and monsters.
Vast riches.
Hidden treasures.
Evil haunts.
Uncharted frontiers.
The mysterious unknown.
The people who are captivated
by the magic in those words…
are called…
Hunters.
[theme music playing]
[Johness] I’ll tear your body apart.
Huh?
[heart beating]
[groans]
LAST TEST X OF X RESOLVE
[narrator]
The Exam’s Third Phase required applicants
to reach Trick Tower’s base
within 72 hours.
But Gon and his friends incurred a penalty
and were forced to wait for 50 hours.
Meanwhile...
[rumble]
[announcer] Geretta, applicant 384,
is the fourth to pass.
Time elapsed, 12 hours and 27 minutes.
Well not bad, I guess.
[board click-clacks]
Be careful not to hesitate
on the first step
or you’re gonna hurt yourself.
-Here.
-I gotcha.
Hey, Kurapika.
Once we’ve finished
spending our 50 hours here,
we’ll have
less than ten hours left, right?
Yes. That’s correct.
Great! [laughs] That’s way more time
than we’ll need, so no harm done!
-You’re a fool.
-What’s that?
The Third Phase of the Hunter Exam
is supposed to take 72 hours.
And each new phase weeds out
more of the applicants
cutting the field roughly in half
every time.
In other words, it’s meant
to take 72 hours on average.
The fact you didn’t know that is proof
that you’re an idiot.
[annoyed grumble]
Then, our chances
of reaching the finish within ten hours
will depend on the remaining trials.
Yeah. I guess you’ve got a point.
Hm. It’s too bad you’re so unlucky
you can’t even win a game
of rock paper scissors when it counts.
What’d you say?!
You deliberately lost a bet just
so you could cop a feel.
Then you picked a game
you didn’t stand a chance of winning.
Hey, shut up!
You surrendered
before your fight even got started!
[Tonpa] I... give up!
Sure, I threw in the towel.
I can admit that.
But, I only wasted a couple of seconds.
-[Leorio grumbles]
-[Tonpa] You didn’t just lose.
You squandered 50 hours
we could really use right now.
The least you could do
is take responsibility.
And besides,
who ever heard of a Hunter
who sucked at gambling?
Shut up!
You don’t even want to become a Hunter!
The only reason you’re here
is to ruin our chances!
[chuckles]
And now you’ll have that guilt
eating away at you
for the rest of this Phase.
[clatter]
Hey! What are you doing?!
Oops! Sorry.
This room isn’t big enough
for skateboarding, so knock it off!
[Gon] Oh...
[snoring loudly]
[Tonpa grunts]
[Kurapika] Can't sleep?
Not really.
Thing is, I can stay awake
two or three days at a time.
[Kurapika] Ten hours down, huh?
[Killua]
With no windows, it’s hard to tell, but…
it’s probably morning.
[Kurapika] Most likely.
[mischievous chuckling]
Huh?
[Killua grunts]
Knock it off, you guys!
[both chuckling]
Some of us are tryin’ to sleep!
[groans] Gross!
[laughing loudly]
[chuckling]
Not funny!
What the hell is wrong with you guys?
-[snores]
-You bastard!
You’d better not just be pretending
to be asleep.
Damn it! Well, I guess I’m awake now.
[grunts] And we’ve still got 40 more hours
left to go.
[snoring]
[tapping]
[Killua] Hm. I thought fishing
was just putting some bait on a hook
and throwing it in the water.
Uh-huh.
But you’ve also gotta think like a fish.
And that’s supposed to work?
Yup!
How would a fish feel if it saw bait
dangling in front of it?
Gimme!
Huh?
Oh, wow!
Let me give it a try!
[concentrating exhale]
So, like this?
[laughs] You missed.
Yeah, but watch this!
[Leorio grunts]
Hey! What the hell
do you think you’re doing?!
Stop!
-Right on target!
-Nice!
Wait! You’re gonna tear my pants!
Knock it off!
-Ya see? I landed a big one.
-Yep.
Do I look like a fish to you?!
Come on! Grow up!
Well, you don’t have to get so mad.
It‘s not like I’m gonna grill you
and eat you.
Just leave me the hell alone!
Can’t a guy just take a nap around here?
[chuckling]
[annoyed grumbling]
[smirks]
[Leorio] What are you smiling about?
[Tonpa] Oh, nothing.
You’re up to something again, aren’t you?
I don’t know what you mean.
All I want
is to spend the rest of our time here
in peace and quiet.
You liar.
I don’t trust you
as far as I could throw ya, got it?
[derisive snort] Feeling’s mutual.
[swoosh]
[chomping quickly]
All right! Goal!
Hm?
[announcer] Pokkle, applicant number 53,
and Goz, applicant number 371,
arrived simultaneously.
Time elapsed, 30 hours and four minutes.
Damn.
Tough luck. A tie goes to
whichever applicant
has the lower number, old man.
[derisive snort]
[Goz]
These guys must be quite skilled indeed.
Hope I get a chance to fight them.
[lightly snoring]
[loud yawn]
[beep]
[footsteps]
[Tonpa] You didn’t just lose.
You squandered 50 hours
we could really use right now.
The least you could do
is take responsibility.
[music plays]
[grunt]
[laughing]
[grunting quietly]
[grunting]
[both grunting]
-[Killua laughs]
-[Gon groans]
[grunts] That hurt!
[yawns]
One more hour.
[sighs]
[chatters quietly]
[announcer] Sommy, applicant number 118
is the thirteenth to pass.
-[chatters quietly]
-Time elapsed 61 hours and 54 minutes.
We’ve still got ten hours left?
Man, I really should’ve taken more time.
[straining]
Okay!
I’m ready to go!
[Kurapika] One more minute…
[Leorio sighs]
This one minute’s taking forever, huh?
[buzzer goes off]
Wait for us, Gon!
[Gon chuckles]
HUNTER GLOSSARY
BORED
[panting]
Thirty minutes of running
and right we’re back where we started.
Didn’t I tell you
we should’ve taken the stairs down?
[yells] This is the route
we all agreed upon,
so why don’t you shut the hell up?!
[all yelling]
[screaming]
[coughing]
[Killua] Man, I’m all covered in dust.
Damn. Only an hour left.
If we don’t hurry, we’ll never make it.
DOOR, O - OPEN, X - CLOSE
[Leorio] We’re supposed to vote
on whether to open the door?
We need to move on,
so the choice is pretty clear.
[short beeps]
[grumbles]
I’ve had enough of your crap!
What are you talking about?
I pressed ‘O’, too!
Don't lie to me!
Sabotaging our chances
is your freakin’ specialty!
-Sorry, Leorio.
-Huh?
I accidentally pressed the wrong button.
What?
[sighs]
-Fine, I see how it is.
-[Tonpa] Hold on.
Hm?
I think you owe me an apology.
You think I’m just gonna let that slide?
Maybe if you weren’t
always doing shady stuff,
this kinda thing wouldn’t happen.
I don’t owe you a thing.
Almost sounds like you’re trying to say
I’m the one to blame
for everything that’s gone wrong.
What’s that?
Don’t tell me. Have you already forgotten
who it was who cost us those 50 hours?
If memory serves,
I’m pretty sure that honor goes to you.
[Leorio grumbles]
-Leorio, calm down.
-[Leorio] Shut up, Kurapika!
C’mon, guys! Knock it off!
I’m the one who pressed the wrong button,
so it’s my fault!
This is stupid.
I’m going on ahead.
Killua, don’t go!
Hey, Gon! We must be getting real close
to the end!
Whoa! Really?
[Killua] Let’s see.
“This will be the last decision
made by majority rule.
Are you ready?
Choose ‘O’ or ‘X’.”
And that’s it.
[Leorio] Am I ready?
Of course, I am! Let’s do this!
-Bastard!
-Let it go!
We don’t have time to argue.
[signal beeping]
[announcer] Please select a path.
There are two available options
to choose from.
The long and difficult path
which the entire group can take,
or the short and easy path
which will be limited
to only three of you.
Incidentally, if you choose
the long and difficult path,
it will require a minimum
of 45 hours to complete.
while the short and easy path
will lead you directly to the goal
in approximately three minutes.
Press ‘O’ to select
the long and difficult path,
or press ‘X’
to choose the short and easy path.
If ‘X’ is selected
two applicants from your group
must be chained to the wall with handcuffs
before the door will open.
Those applicants will be unable to move
until the time limit has expired.
[Killua]
The Examiners thought of everything.
Look around.
Every weapon I’ve ever heard of
is down here.
So, two out of five, huh?
Then they must expect us to fight
to decide which three pass.
[Leorio] All right.
I want to make this clear.
I’m pressing the ‘X’ button.
But I’m not staying behind.
I’m one of the three that’s moving on
and I’ll do whatever it takes.
[Tonpa] You’re one to talk.
We coulda taken the long path
if you hadn’t wasted 50 hours.
Why don’t you do the right thing
and make up for it by staying behind?
What’s that?!
I’m sure we all agree.
What about it, guys? Did I lie?
[Gon] Hold on a second!
I’m going to press ‘O’.
It’s just we all made it this far
by working together.
We should finish together.
Gon…
[Gon] It’s a big risk. I know that.
But still, we’ve got to try!
Oh, come on!
It’s not a question of being a risk.
We’ve got less than an hour.
[exhales defiantly]
Gon. There’s only one way to pass.
I mean, it’s obvious.
Well, there you have it, kid.
So, now we have to pick
which three advance.
If it was up to me,
you and I are two of ‘em, Gon.
[smirks]
Well, I’ve made it this far.
No way I’m stopping now.
Whoever makes the first move wins.
Is this really what it’s come to?
We have to fight amongst ourselves?
[Tonpa yelling]
That was a cheap shot!
In a fight, there’s no such thing
as a cheap shot!
[Leorio screaming]
Bastard!
Stop it! Both of you!
Yeah! Come on! Let’s all do this together!
We don’t have to start fighting
until we choose ‘O’ or ‘X’, you idiot!
It’s too late for that!
Then I guess
I’ll just have to choose for you!
Well, two can play at that game!
Looks like fighting is our only option.
[Kurapika] What do we do?
[announcer] Three minutes remain.
It’s finally over, huh?
Yeah. Feels like it took forever.
Huh?
[tired panting]
I...
made...
it.
[Imori] He's dead.
[Umori] Damn, what a moron.
It's better to survive
and try again next year
than to pass and die tryin’.
[announcer] One minute remains.
That’s it, then.
Looks like it’s just the 19 of us
that are already here.
[muffled rumble]
Hm...
Hm?
[announcer] Kurapika, number 404,
is the twentieth to pass.
Killua, number 99,
is the twenty-first to pass.
Gon, number 405,
is the twenty-second to pass.
Time elapsed 71 hours and 59 minutes.
Boy, my butt hurts!
I certainly wasn’t expecting
the short and easy path to be a slide.
[Hisoka] Three of them, eh?
[announcer] Thirty seconds remain.
Even with that big slide,
that was really close!
My hands are covered in blisters.
[Leorio] Same here.
[grunting]
[announcer] Leorio, number 403,
is the twenty-third to pass.
Tonpa, number 16,
is the twenty-fourth to pass.
Time elapsed 71 hours and 59 minutes.
[Leorio] My hands are wrecked
but all five of us
cleared the tower together, didn’t we?
And it’s all thanks to Gon!
[grunting]
[Kurapika]
We entered the long and difficult path,
broke down the wall
and from there,
we snuck into the short and easy one.
I can’t believe it.
You came up with that plan on the spot!
I figured we could use those weapons
to break through the walls.
But it did take
almost all the time we had left.
[Kurapika] Even under pressure,
you were able to calmly assess our options
and think of a way to get around them.
And that is what makes you so special.
[buzzer rings]
[announcer] The Third Phase
of the Hunter Exam is over!
Twenty-five applicants have passed,
including one deceased.
[narrator]
Although they had their differences,
Gon found a way to bring them all together
and complete the trial as a team.
But today’s friend may be tomorrow’s foe.
What Gon doesn’t know is that before long,
they will be forced to face each other
in savage individual battles.
[theme song playing]
[Gon] Next time: "Letter x From x Gon!"
[Mito] Always gone!
[Gon] Who, me?